Guide to the Garnsey family papers, 1847-1993.
Garnsey family papers, 1847-1993.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Garnsey family papers, 1847-1993.
2984
Garnsey family.
1.9 cubic ft.
Diaries, a scrapbook, correspondence, estate and financial papers, a family history, research materials, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes diaries, 1850-71; scrapbook about Cyrus Garnsey III and World War I, compiled by his father, Cyrus Garnsey Jr.; letters to Cyrus Garnsey and Mercy Harris Garnsey from Ira Harris, 1847-70; personal letters, clippings, and telegrams, 1917-51, collected by Cyrus Garnsey Jr. about his work with the United States Fuel Administration; estate and financial papers relating to Cyrus Garnsey Jr., Mary Woolsey Pettis and other Garnsey family members, primarily concerning Lakeholme, the Garnsey family home in Seneca Falls, N.Y.; letters, notes, clippings, and research materials about the Sullivan Expedition, historical markers, the Johnston Farm, the Montezuma Marsh bird refuge, Luke Swetland, Judge William I.Grubb, and other interests of Cyrus Garnsey Jr.; also a family history by Elizabeth Pettis Lamb, 1984; and letters relating to the Iroquois turtle shell rattle from Chief Jesse Lyons, Chief of the Onondagas. Maps and letters relating to Cayuga Lake Park; early material relating to Cyrus Garnsey's attending Brown University and his obituaries; Croix de Guerre and memorial certificate for Cyrus Garnsey III, who died in World War I; and letters and pictures relating to Cyrus Garnsey, Jr. and his resemblance to Robert E. Lee.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes diaries, 1850-71; scrapbook about Cyrus Garnsey III and World War I, compiled by his father, Cyrus Garnsey Jr.; letters to Cyrus Garnsey and Mercy Harris Garnsey from Ira Harris, 1847-70; personal letters, clippings, and telegrams, 1917-51, collected by Cyrus Garnsey Jr. about his work with the United States Fuel Administration; estate and financial papers relating to Cyrus Garnsey Jr., Mary Woolsey Pettis and other Garnsey family members, primarily concerning Lakeholme, the Garnsey family home in Seneca Falls, N.Y.; letters, notes, clippings, and research materials about the Sullivan Expedition, historical markers, the Johnston Farm, the Montezuma Marsh bird refuge, Luke Swetland, Judge William I.Grubb, and other interests of Cyrus Garnsey Jr.; also a family history by Elizabeth Pettis Lamb, 1984; and letters relating to the Iroquois turtle shell rattle from Chief Jesse Lyons, Chief of the Onondagas
Maps and letters relating to Cayuga Lake Park; early material relating to Cyrus Garnsey's attending Brown University and his obituaries; Croix de Guerre and memorial certificate for Cyrus Garnsey III, who died in World War I; and letters and pictures relating to Cyrus Garnsey, Jr. and his resemblance to Robert E. Lee.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Garnsey family.; Garnsey, Cyrus,; Garnsey, Cyrus, Jr.; Garnsey, Cyrus, III.; Harris, Ira.; Lamb, Elizabeth Pettis.; Pettis, Mary Woolsey.; Lyons, Jesse.; United States.Fuel Administration.
Subjects:
Agriculture.; Family--New York (State)--Seneca Falls.
Places:
United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--Campaigns.; Seneca County (N.Y.)--History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Diaries, 1850-1871
  Each contain same accounts at the end
  - Jan. 1850-Jan. 1851 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 1851-Dec. 1852 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 1852-Jan. 1853 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 1853-Jan. 1854 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 1854-Mar. 1855 (Box 1)
  - Mar.-Nov. 1955 (Box 1)
  - Nov. 1855-Sept. 1856 (Box 1)
  - Aug. 1856-July 1857 (Box 1)
  - July 1857-May 1858 (Box 1)
  - May 1858-Sept. 1859 (Box 1)
  - Aug. 1859-June 1860 (Box 1)
  - July 1861-Oct. 1862 (Box 1)
  - Oct. 1862-Feb. 1864 (Box 1)
  - Mar. 1864-Dec. 1865 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 1866-Jan. 1868 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 1869-Jan. 1871 (Box 1)
- Photocopies of diaries (Box 2-3)
- Scrapbook of Cyrus Garnsey III put together by his father (Cyrus Garnsey Jr.) about Cyrus Garnsey III's participation in World War I (Box 4)
- Letters to Cyrus (nephew of) and Mercy (sister of) Ira Harris, 1847-1849 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Letters to Cyrus and Mercy from Ira Harris, 1850 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Letters to Cyrus and Mercy from Ira Harris, 1851 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Letters to Cyrus and Mercy from Ira Harris, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Letters to Cyrus and Mercy from Ira Harris, 1853-1855 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Letters to Cyrus and Mercy from Ira Harris, 1856-1857 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Letters to Cyrus and Mercy from Ira Harris, 1861-1870 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Ira Harris Family Papers (Box 5, Folder 8)
- [From Binder] Personal letters, clippings, and telegrams; Cyrus Garnsey Jr. - United States Fuel Administration
  - 1917 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1918 Jan.-Feb. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1918 May 3-4 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1918 May 5-8 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1918 May 9-14 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 1918 May 16-29 (includes Woodrow Wilson letter) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 1918 June-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 1919 Jan.-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 1920 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 1921-1927 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 1937-1951 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Skit by Washington Newspapermen (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Typescript of diary, 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Certificates and proclamations (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Estate papers of Cyrus Garnsey, Jr. (Box 5, Folder 23-24)
- Correspondence about Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s finances with Mary Woolsey Pettis (Box 5, Folder 25-26)
- Correspondence about Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s finances with Mary Woolsey Pettis, also inventory of homestead, and clerk's certificate of the search of the premises of Homer A. Newell (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Assessment of property of Cyrus Garnsey Jr., 1853 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Contract with Thomas Reynolds and Cyrus Garnsey, 1856 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Letters, notes, clippings, and research on the Sullivan Expedition and the placing of historical markers (by Cyrus Garnsey Jr.) (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- Annotated map of the Sullivan Expedition (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Notes on historical markers (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Clippings on historical markers (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s papers about Johnston Farm (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s Johnston farm blueprints (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s collected articles about Johston farm (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s papers about Montezuma Marsh bird refuge (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s collected papers about Luke Swetland (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s collected desk notes and small notebook dated "March 4, 1885 - Cleveland and Hendricks Inauguration" (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s collected clippings and notes on lotteries and gambling (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s collected notes about Judge William I. Grubb (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Papers to Cyrus Garnsey Jr. from Sanford Morison about Alabama Mines, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Misc. about career of Cyrus Garnsey Jr. (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Cyrus Garnsey Jr.'s calendar (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Misc. papers of Cyrus Garnsey Jr. (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Family of Cyrus Garnsey Jr. Genealogy by Elizabeth Pettis Lamb, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Reprint of the "Method of Fixing Prices of Bituminous Coal adopted by the United States Fuel Administration," by Cyrus Garnsey Jr., R.V. Norris, and J.H. Allport, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Memorials of Ira Harris, 1876 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- A Genealogy of Nicholas Harris, M.D., 1904 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Sullivan's Campaign, A. Tiffany Norton, 1879 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- "A Logical State Park Project" (Red Jacket Memorial Park), and items by Alexander M. Stewart with signature (Box 6, Folder 26)
- An Addition to the Garnsey Family History, typescript by Elizabeth Lamb, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 27)